Aaron Craig's CV

Contact Info Phone: 027 755 2760 24 Mein Street

Email: aaroncraig@protonmail.ch Newtown, Wellington, 6021

Website: github.com/craigthelinguist

Skills Programming Languages: Java, C, Python, Haskell, Prolog, SQL

Modelling Languages: Alloy, UML, LTSA

Markup Languages: Latex, Markdown, JSON, XML

Libraries & Frameworks: JUnit, pandas, matplotlib, numpy, curses, OpenGL, XStream, Berkeley

Socket API, Swing, Unity. **Protocols**: HTTP, DNS.

Job History

Victoria University, Wellington

Research Assistant

Oct 2015 – Mar 2016

- Contribute to the Wyvern interpreter: github.com/wyvernlang/wyvern
- Design a logic for specifying and verifying architectural constraints.
- My supervisor was Alex Potanin.

New Zealand Registry Services, Wellington

Research Intern

Oct 2014 – Mar 2015

- Analysis and summary of DNS data using pandas, matplotlib.
- Detection and classification of botnet domains using clustering techniques.
- Helped gather and verify data used to generate a map of the NZ internet's routing topology.

Victoria University, Wellington

Sessional Assistant & Tutor

Mar 2014 - Oct 2015

- Marking tests and assignments; invigilating.
- Running tutorials, labs, and helpdesks.
- Classes tutored: Intro to Computer Science; Engineering Modelling & Design; Data Structures & Algorithms II; Formal Foundations of Programming.

Converga Ltd., Petone

Business Processing Clerk

Nov 2013 - Mar 2014

- Data entry and verification.
- Sorting files by hand. (I did this using radix sort)

Target Furniture, Porirua

Temp, Storeperson

Nov 2010 - May 2013

- Furniture removal, delivery, assembly, and repair.
- Managing inventory.
- Driving forklift.
- Training temps.
- Assisting and greeting customers.

Interests & Projects

Natural & Programming Languages. I'm interested in the structure of languages. This includes: compilers, programming language design, and natural language processing. I have made several corpora for Māori and NZ English. I have my own SAT solver that I've been tinkering with. At NZRS I did research into detecting botnets by classifying domain names. As part of that I gave a presentation at the 2015 New Zealand Internet Research Forum.

Visualisations. At NZRS I helped verify data used to generate a map of the New Zealand internet. I have implemented several interactive algorithm visualisations (A*, Kruskal's, Knight's Tour, KNN).

Computer Science Education. My work in computer science pedagogy keeps me sharp in a diverse number of areas. I am writing an introductory textbook of computer science, partly motivated by my experience as a student.

Game Development. Each year I attend Pixeljam, a Wellington-based gamejam. We've several flavours of game, such as a 2d lane-runner, a 2d platformer, and a 3d horror game. Recently I started working on a 2d game engine in Java, built atop OpenGL.

EDUCATION

Victoria University of Wellington, New Zealand

• STAR Programme	2011
BA Linguistics & Philosophy	2012
• BSc Computer Science & Mathematics	2013 - Current

Tawa College, New Zealand

• NCEA Level 3 (Merit endorsement).

2011

Scholarships & Awards

Victoria University of Wellington

• Victoria Achievers Scholarship 2012

NZQA

• Outstanding English Scholarship 2011

Tawa College

• Katherine Mansfield Award (English)	2011
• Leanne Dixon Cup (History)	2011

LANGUAGES

English

Māori (Elementary)

ABOUT ME

I was born in Porirua and live in Wellington. I like reading history, philosophy, and literature. I did amateur boxing for two years but nowadays just like to watch. My tribe is Muaūpoko, in Horowhenua.

References

Available upon request.